Localization is all about estimating the probability distribution of the state xt,
ローカライゼーションはすべてステート xt の確率分布の推測で
which is the pose of the car,
これが車の向きになります
another condition that all previous observations that,
別の条件では時間 1 から t までの
from time 1 to t,
すべての以前の観測値
and all previous controls u,
および時間 1 から t までの
from time 1 to t, are given.
すべての以前の制御 u の推定に関するものです
To solve the pure localization problem,
純粋にローカライゼーションの問題を解決するには
we assume the map is correct and does not change.
地図は正しく 変わってないと想定します
Therefore, the map is also given.
よって 地図も提供されます
If we would like to estimate also the map,
地図も推測する場合は
then we would solve the simultaneous localization and mapping problem,
同時に発生するローカライゼーションと地図作成に関する問題を解決するか
or called SLAM problem,
より複雑な SLAM と呼ばれる
which is much more complex.
問題を解決します
But today I don't talk about this.
今日は これについてはお話ししません
Today, I will talk about the posterior distribution right here.
今日は ここで事後分布について話します
Before we go deeper into math,
数式を詳しく見ていく前に
I want to show you how we define
特定の 1D ローカライゼーションシナリオに
the different input data for a specific 1D localization scenario.
異なる入力データをどのように定義するかをお見せします
This means I will explain how the car is sensing and moving.
これは 車がどのように検知して動いているのかを説明するということです
I will also show you how the map looks.
また地図がどのように見えるかもお見せします
This example is very similar to what you already learned with Sebastian.
この例は セバスチャンと既に学習したことと とてもよく似ています
So, let's talk about the map first.
さて でまず地図について説明します
The map includes the position of street lamps and trees in 1D.
地図には 1D の道路の凸凹や木の場所が含まれています
This means we are working with landmark-based maps which are,
これは ランドマークをベースにした地図で作業していることを意味し
in general, more sparse than grid-based maps.
通常 グリッドベースの地図に比べて稀です
In the 1D case,
1D の場合
the map is a vector of the position where these objects are.
地図はこれらのオブジェクトがある位置のベクトルです
Here, the map includes six landmarks with the values 9, 15, 25, 31, 59, and 77.
ここでは 6 つの目印があります 値はそれぞれ 9 15 25 31 59 77 です
For the observation we
観測値の場合
state that the car measures the nearest k,
車は運転方向の一番近くの
seen static objects, in driving direction.
静止オブジェクト k を測定することがわかっています
So we assume that the car can detect the distances to street lamps and trees.
だから 車は道路の凸凹と木の距離を検出できると推定します
This results in an observation list which includes,
観測リストのこの結果から
for each time stamp t,
タイムスタンプ t 毎に
a vector of distances zt,
1 から k 番目
from 1 to zt to
までの距離ベクター zt が
k. It is possible that we detect multiple trees or street lamps at a time stamp t,
が含まれています タイムスタンプ t で複数の木や道の凸凹を検出したり
or detect nothing at all.
あるいは何も検出しないこともあり得ます
The control vector includes a direct move of the car between consecutive time stamps.
コントロールベクトルには 連続したタイムスタンプ間の車の直接の動きが含まれます
This means the control is defined by
これは コントロールは
the distance the car traveled between t and t minus 1.
t とt－1の間の車の移動距離で定義されることを意味します
In this case, the car moves 2 meters to the right.
この場合では 車は 2 メートル右に動きます
The true pose of the car is somewhere on the mapped area.
実際の車の向きは地図上のどこかにあります
Since the map is discrete,
地図は離散なので
the pose of the car could be any integer between 0 and 99 meters.
車の向きは 0 ～ 99 のいずれかの整数になります
This means the belief of xt is defined as a vector of hundred elements,
これは xt の信念は 100 個の要素のベクトルで定義され
and each element represents
それぞれの要素は
a probability that the car is located at the corresponding position.
車が関連の位置に配置される確率を表します
The goal is now to estimate these values.
ここでの目標はこれらの値を推定することです